<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.Loganavter.Improve-ImgSLI</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Improve ImgSLI</name>
  <summary>Image comparison with magnifier</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Improve ImgSLI is a versatile open-source tool designed for detailed side-by-side image comparison. Easily spot differences and inspect fine details using its synchronized magnifying glass feature. Ideal for designers, photographers, AI art/upscaling enthusiasts, and anyone needing precise visual analysis.
    </p>
    <p>Key features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Compare images with an adjustable horizontal or vertical split line.</li>
      <li>Use the powerful synchronized magnifier with flexible controls: adjustable capture/display size, position control (mouse and WASD/QE keys), view freezing, and combined magnifiers.</li>
      <li>Load single or multiple images per comparison panel via drag-and-drop or file dialogs.</li>
      <li>Easily switch between loaded images using dropdown selectors.</li>
      <li>Save the complete comparison view (including split line, magnifier markers, and optional filenames) as a full-resolution image.</li>
      <li>Swap image lists between panels with a single click.</li>
      <li>Edit displayed file names directly within the interface.</li>
      <li>Multi-language interface (English, Russian, Chinese, Brazilian Portuguese) with persistent settings.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      The application is intuitive and distributed under the free MIT License.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/Loganavter/Improve-ImgSLI</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.Loganavter.Improve-ImgSLI.desktop</launchable>     
<screenshots>
  <screenshot type="default">
    <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.1/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/flatpak_1.png</image>
    <caption>Vertical caption</caption>
  </screenshot>
  <screenshot>
    <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.1/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/flatpak_2.png</image>
    <caption>Horizontal caption</caption>
  </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
    <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.1/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/flatpak_3.png</image>
    <caption>List option</caption>
  </screenshot>
</screenshots>
      
      
<developer id="io.github.loganavter">
  <name>Loganavter</name>
</developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="3.1.9" date="2025-04-15"/>
  </releases>
</component>
