<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.Loganavter.Improve-ImgSLI</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Improve ImgSLI</name>
  <summary>Image comparison with magnifier</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Improve ImgSLI is an open-source image comparison tool focused on precise visual inspection, responsive interaction, and advanced rendering workflows. It is designed for artists, photographers, retouchers, AI upscaling workflows, quality control, and anyone who needs to compare images at pixel level without losing context.
    </p>
    <p>Key features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Compare images with a movable horizontal or vertical split line, including zooming and panning in the main canvas.</li>
      <li>Use a synchronized magnifier with adjustable capture area, display size, freeze mode, combined layouts, internal split, and keyboard-assisted positioning.</li>
      <li>Load and manage multiple images per side with drag-and-drop, list switching, swapping, and direct filename editing.</li>
      <li>Inspect visual differences with rendering-aware preview controls and selectable interpolation modes.</li>
      <li>Export full-resolution comparison images with overlays, labels, and comparison state preserved.</li>
      <li>Edit recorded comparison sessions in the built-in video editor with timeline selection, trimming, preview playback, and export.</li>
      <li>Run on multiple rendering backends with improved compatibility across Wayland, X11, and Windows environments.</li>
      <li>Use persistent settings, multilingual interface support, and structured diagnostics for advanced troubleshooting.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      The application is distributed under the MIT License.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/Loganavter/Improve-ImgSLI</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.Loganavter.Improve-ImgSLI.desktop</launchable>     
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.8.0/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/screenshot_1.jpg</image>
      <caption>Magnifier</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.8.0/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/screenshot_2.jpg</image>
      <caption>Difference View</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Loganavter/media_archive/1.8.0/Improve_ImgSLI/screenshots/screenshot_3.jpg</image>
      <caption>Video Editor</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <developer id="io.github.loganavter">
    <name>Loganavter</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="8.2.0" date="2026-04-05">
      <description>
        <p>A compatibility and rendering patch release focused on startup stability, backend behavior, and high-DPI correctness.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved startup behavior by removing problematic top-level prewarm and reveal paths that could cause compositor artifacts on KDE Wayland and transient miniature windows on Windows.</li>
          <li>Switched the application toward the Quick canvas path for more predictable cross-platform behavior and reduced native OpenGL window-management issues.</li>
          <li>Fixed multiple rendering and interaction edge cases related to split view synchronization during zoom and pan.</li>
          <li>Improved high-DPI and viewport mapping correctness, reducing geometry mismatches between rendered content and interactive hit areas.</li>
          <li>Fixed magnifier edge behavior, overlay clamping, and capture-ring rendering so interaction near image borders remains accurate.</li>
          <li>Aligned export, preview, and canvas backend behavior more closely after the rendering-layer refactor.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="8.1.0" date="2026-03-30">
      <description>
        <p>A major release consolidating months of deep architectural work and introducing significant new features.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Hybrid CPU-GPU rendering: a new rendering engine capable of offloading work to the GPU via OpenGL shaders for dramatically improved performance on large images.</li>
          <li>Canvas architecture overhaul: the comparison canvas was fully rewritten for correctness and performance across all operating modes and edge cases.</li>
          <li>Native Qt widgets: all pop-up and overlay windows are now native Qt widgets, greatly improving Wayland compatibility.</li>
          <li>Canvas zooming and panning: the main comparison view can now be zoomed and panned interactively.</li>
          <li>Video editor improvements: the timeline was rewritten with keyframe-based model, aspect-ratio-correct thumbnails, and dynamic spacing.</li>
          <li>Plugin-based architecture for extensibility and a cleaner internal structure.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="7.9.0" date="2025-10-27">
      <description>
        <p>This release includes various improvements and bug fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="6.2.0" date="2025-08-16">
      <description>
        <p>This is the most extensive architectural refactoring in the project's history, transitioning the entire application to a robust and modern Model-View-Presenter (MVP) pattern. This update establishes a new, stable foundation for future development and introduces a completely custom-built UI.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Complete Architectural Overhaul: The codebase is now fully modular and based on the MVP pattern, significantly improving stability and maintainability. Many underlying bugs have been passively fixed as a result.</li>
          <li>New Custom UI: The third-party `PyQt-Fluent-Widgets` library has been removed and replaced with a custom-built set of "fluent-style" components. This removes GPL licensing constraints and gives the application a more unique design.</li>
          <li>Enhanced Image List Management: The image selection flyout is now a powerful two-panel manager with full drag-and-drop support for reordering and moving images between lists.</li>
          <li>New and Reimagined Dialogs: Introduced a dedicated, feature-rich Export dialog and a redesigned, easier-to-navigate Help window.</li>
          <li>Improved Caching: The caching system has been upgraded from two to three levels for even smoother performance during interactive use.</li>
          <li>Reduced Package Size: The removal of the external UI library has decreased the application's overall size on some platforms.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="5.8.20" date="2025-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>This is a major quality-of-life and rendering engine update.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Overhauled the core update logic to a reactive, state-driven architecture, significantly improving stability and eliminating a class of race-condition bugs.</li>
          <li>The magnifier can now render outside the image boundaries and correctly handles horizontal split view.</li>
          <li>Added smooth, anti-aliased borders for the magnifier and capture area for better visual quality.</li>
          <li>Added long-press actions for swapping and clearing images/lists to speed up workflow.</li>
          <li>Image selection dropdowns are now scrollable with the mouse wheel.</li>
          <li>Added a new setting to permanently enable or disable debug logging.</li>
          <li>Replaced all internal print statements with a structured logging system.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="4.9.0" date="2025-06-05">
      <description>
        <p>This release introduces a major user interface overhaul and performance improvements.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The application interface has been completely redesigned using the modern `qfluentwidgets` style.</li>
          <li>The image caching service has been significantly improved, resulting in a much smoother experience.</li>
          <li>Refactored the core rendering code for better performance and easier maintenance.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.1.9" date="2025-04-15">
      <description>
        <p>This release focuses on settings persistence and bug fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added window state persistence: the app now remembers its size and position between sessions.</li>
          <li>Introduced a new Settings dialog to centralize application preferences.</li>
          <li>Added options to configure UI language, JPEG save quality, and the maximum length of displayed filenames.</li>
          <li>Addressed several critical bugs to improve stability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
